- Subtitled by CrazyIvan -
Psagmeno.com
MOViE iNFO WiTH .srt FiLES!
Have you not heard?
The Lord is the everlasting God.
Creator of the ends of the earth.
He will not grow tired or wary.
And his understanding
no one can fathom.
He gives strength to the weary.
And increases the power to the weak.
Even you grow tired and weary.
And young man stumble and fall
But those who hope in the Lord.
Will renew their strength.
They will soar on wings like eagles.
They will run
And not be weary.
They will walk.
And not be frightened.
Desmond.
Hang on.
Hang on, Desmond.
We're gonna get you outta here.
Desmond.
What.
Wait up.
Catch up.
Wait up. I got
something to tell you.
What Hal?
Race you to the top.
Hey cheater.
See you later slowpoke.
Hey.
Wanna hand?
I got it.
Saved ya.
Ah, you don't. Quit it.
You quit it.
God sake.
Hey, get away from that ledge.
You damn fool kids.
You gonna break your neck.
It's them Doss kids.
Crazy as their old man.
They dug up the corner of Jack's remain.
Put him in the sidewalk.
You boys won't recognize it now.
Mind you I doubt
they'll recognize you.
They hardly know me
when I walked by.
It's like I died with you.
It's like we boys never existed.
Well that's all I
got for you today.
Block him with your
right Desmond.
Stop it.
Do you hear me.
What are they fighting about?
When did they ever
needed a reason.
Hey Tom do you
Why stop and save me
whipping them both.
This way I'd whip
the one that wins.
Tom.
No.
Oh God.
Tom.
Wake up.
Can you hear me?
What the hell did you done?
He can't hear me.
We'll get some ice.
You shift that basket.
I got it.
Is he breathing?
Hal?
Hal can you hear me?
Come on.
Dear God help him.
Hal?
What do you think you doing?
I'm going to have to beat you now.
You know the rules.
You hear me Desmond?
Desmond!
Tom. Stop.
It's not going to teach the boy.
His violence enough already.
Like I find you go smothering and kiss him.
You tell him the world
is soft and gentle place.
Hal's gonna be okay.
Hey.
I could've killed him.
Yes, you could have.
Murder is the worst sin of all.
And to take another man's life.
That is the most egregious
sin in Lord's eye.
Nothing hurts His heart the most.
I hate him.
Mama.
Why does he hate us so much?
Oh he don't hate us.
He hates himself.
Sometimes.
Your daddy and I met the real him.
I wish you knew him like
I did before the war.
How do we sound Desmond?
Like a heavenly host angels, Mom.
Now you know it's a
sin to tell a lie.
Especially in this place.
Well I never said they
were singing angels.
What's going on out there, Desmond?
Go on. Get him out.
Get him out.
Drag him out.
Just tug.
I'll phone an ambulance.
No.
No time.
Joshua your pick up?
Quick.
Okay.
You gonna be fine, man.
You gonna be fine.
You in good hand.
What do we got here.
That's a severed artery.
- Get some sutures.
- Yes, doctor.
Put some pressure on it.
Did you apply this tourniquet?
Yes, sir.
Nice work. You might've
save this boy's life.
You staying with us.
You'll be okay.
We can get that.
Stay with us.
You should be okay.
You feel okay?
Certainly doc.
Army physical is that way.
This is for giving blood.
Are you alright?
Oh no. That's not mine.
I'm fine.
Thank you for asking though maam.
What do you need?
My belt.
I lend it to the boy
who had the accident.
My pants don't hold up
so good without it.
Well I dont' have your belt.
No. I know that maam. It's
out there with the boys still.
Okay.
I'm just here to take blood.
I'll give you mine.
Okay.
Go to that room over there.
Wait with the others.
I'll call you here.
That. That room.
You ever given blood before, Mr.
Doss.
But my friends call me Desmond.
No, maam this is my first time.
I always dream about
being a doctor but ahhh
Didn't get much school.
Might be a little dizzy when we're done.
Somebody picking you up?
No, maam.
I'm walking back.
Where do you live?
Fort Ham, Maam.
That's away.
Five or six miles.
I cut through the woods.
Seven that way.
Must really like the woods.
Yes maam.
Sure do.
Okay.
Put some pressure here.
You okay?
Where are you going looking
all spruce and nice?
Met someone yesterday.
Nurse over at the hospital name Dorothy
Schutte and I'm gonna marry her.
Goodness, does she know that?
Well not yet but about to.
Do you have even spoken to a woman?
Other than the one that's not family.
Spoke to her.
In that case, come give
your brother a big hug.
Oh hell. Get your greasy paws off of me.
Wish me luck mama.
Good luck.
Next.
Grab a seat.
You ever been given blood before?
Yes maam I have.
You the belt man.
Desmond that's me.
Well Desmond we can't take
your blood two days in a row.
That's good.
Can we get mine back?
You what?
My blood I need it back.
It dont work like that.
We can't just give it back to you.
Well you got to.
Ever since you stuck me with that
needle my heart is beating up fast.
Every time I think about
you beat faster still.
I never heard that one before.
It's pretty corny.
It is.
Yeah.
That's a shame. I've been
practicing that all night.
No good?
I didn't say that.
What's the difference between
an artery and a vein?
What are you talking about?
The boy's accident.
Arteries spurt blood.
And veins?
Bleed.
I think you need to
practice your boys and
girls dating talk at home
before you come out.
I probably do.
I give you a book if you that interested.
On dating?
On blood.
Another medical question perhaps?
No, I just think you're the
prettiest thing I ever seen.
That's cause I'm
sitting in the dark.
No.
And you're beautiful.
Out of the way!
You need to watch
where you going.
I'm sorry I didn't
think you mind.
You didn't ask.
I thought you might've like it.
Well I might've if you asked.
You coming?
Shit!
Why didn't you say anything to us?
Cause you would've try and talk me out of
it and know what I'm doing is right.
And what about His commandment?
It's not killing in a war.
I would protected lots of boys
from our church from going.
There's a war
and they need men.
Working in a paper mill aren't
going to save this country.
Looks like a movie star.
Huh boy?
Nice uniform.
Good hat.
Reminds me how hard he getting in his look
in this uniform when we went to France.
Remember him Dorothy?
Don't Tom.
What?
I'm just saying how snappy
Hal looks in his uniform.
All you girls certainly
seems to think so.
He had them flocking to him.
He was most proud.
I just hope that when all hell get shot
it's through the front of his jacket.
Like a simple entry wound
not what you miss.
Already got hit in the back.
It blew most of his
guts and intestines out his
front awful everywhere.
Wrecked his uniform entirely.
It was lucky he was dead so he never
knew how awful his uniform looked.
Get out of my sight.
What are you park mountain guard.
Are you gonna help
me Desmond Doss?
Or you just gonna leave me stranded?
I'll help you.
But it's gonna cost you.
What?
A kiss.
That is pure blackmail.
Well yes maam it is but
that is still my condition.
As indeed.
I gonna hold you to it.
Hold on now.
You ain't gonna slap me
are you?
Cause I'll fall off I'm
gonna take you with me.
Kiss me and find out.
What?
I have to enlist.
I can't stay here while
all them go fight for me.
Yes, you can.
- You can stay here.
- Dorothy I have to.
I will be a medic.
I figure I'll be saving
people not killing.
I have to go to work and
don't want to be late.
Dorothy. Don't.
Dorothy. Dorothy.
So are you gonna ask me
to marry you or what?
I don't know you
still gonna hate me?
I wouldn't know you haven't ask.
Well I'm asking you.
With all my heart.
Will you marry me?
Then yes.
Yes I will.
When?
Soon as you get your first leave.
But I still don't like you at this moment.
Yeah.
Okay.
I love you.
Shhhh.
Mama say come see you here.
These three were my best friends.
I grew up with them.
Got into trouble with them.
Chase girls with them.
I enlisted with them.
Then my friends are there.
Covered in dirt and grass eaten by worms.
I don't want to have to visit my sons here.
Daddy I signed up already.
I couldn't do otherwise pop.
- Everybody else is doing it.
- You ain't everybody else.
Everybody else jumps
in does thing quick
without thinking like
damn idiot fools we were.
You know that soldiers who live they
live cause they can do that. You can't!
You got to sit and think
and pray about everything.
Look at you.
You're doing it right now.
You won't be able to live
with yourself if you go.
No, I won't be able to live
with myself if I don't.
I'm going to be a medic.
That's going to be my way to serve.
There you go thinking it all out.
What you figure this war is
going to fit in with you?
Your ideas?
What I know I don't doubt
it's going to be hard.
It won't be hard.
It will be impossible.
You know whatever.
beliefs you had in your
crazy head now.
They don't ever play out
it don't work that way.
And if by certain I don't
know miracle chance you
survive you won't be
giving no thanks to God.
Break. Break. We all need some air.
C'mon fellas shake a leg. I'd understand
you got to say goodbye to mama.
C'mon.
Ladies please! Step away from the bus.
I almost forgot.
Do I need a crowbar.
Here.
I want you to have this.
It's mine.
You keep it right here.
Where I'll be.
I love you.
Do I have to gaze at your deformity
every time I walk to my bed.
Gaze upon it in envy my friend.
You okay there?
You look lost.
Or you can sit right here.
Nice choice.
It got views to the
mountain down to lake.
Randall Fuller.
Desmond Doss.
Call him 'Teach'.
You won't understand
a word he says.
That because no one
else here can read.
But testicles there belong to
a man calling himself 'Hollywood'.
They look like they
belong to a smaller guy.
You know testicles.
Oh hey.
I just got this shoes.
Hey ya.
Grease Nolan out of Redwood.
Where you from?
- Virginia.
- Will Billy huh?
You marry your first cousin?
Haha just joking.
Woah!
That Smitty over there
with Kirzinski's ass.
Like you were doing any
better chowder head.
Hey, I didn't want to embarrassed you.
Wal Kirzinski.
Nice to meet you.
Hey Ping Pong.
What you say your name was?
Desmond Doss.
That Tex Lewis over there.
Thinks he some kind of cowboy.
And Vito Rinnelli.
Now he maybe small
but he is a bulldog.
- Hi how you doing?
- Desmond.
This handsome guy right
here is Lucky Ford.
Hey.
That's Walker and Pinnick over there.
Pretending they're card shufflers.
Pipe down greasy alright.
Unless you want to put
money where your mouth is.
Oh hey.
Good Book right?
- Right.
- I think ahh
I think Lucky's got a good book,
right Lucky?
It's a good read.
Attention!
Ow!
Line up. Move it.
Let's go.
Move it. Move it.
You're a strange looking individual
if you don't mind me saying so Private?
Name?
Andy Walker.
How long have you been dead son?
Sir?
I am not sir.
I am Sergeant Howell or Sarge.
Sir you say for useless people.
The name is Ghoul you say.
Walker.
Sergeant.
It is.
Yes, Sergeant.
There's something off with
your presentation Private.
Can't place it.
Is it your hair?
Is it the wrinkle in your trousers?
I have a knife in
my foot Sergeant.
Oh yes. Of course.
That's it the knife.
What is your name soldier?
Smitty Riker.
No. Your name is Private Idiot.
You know why?
Cause I have a knife in my foot.
Who place the knife there Private?
It was an accident Sergeant.
I was playing stretch.
I'm hardened by the knowledge you
did not placed it there with intention.
Who threw the knife?
I did Sergeant.
Private Kirzinski.
You're part Indian.
What tribe do you belong, son?
Don't know I'm polish.
Wrong.
I believe you must have
Cherokee or Shawnee blood in you.
- No Sir.
- Are you contradicting me?
You son of a bitch.
No sergeant.
Let me see your Indian war cry son.
I don't.
What is your animal spirit?
- Are you a Garter snake?
- No Sergeant.
- Are you a chipmunk?
- No, sergeant.
- Are you a dancing reindeer?
- No sergeant.
- Are you contradicting me Private?
Good.
Then I shall henceforth call you Chief.
As a sign of great respect to your people.
Thank you, sergeant.
Are you grinning at me boy
or is that your natural state?
No Sergeant.
Name private.
Desmond Doss.
I have seen stocks of corn
with better physiques.
Makes you wanna pull an ear off Private.
Can you carry your weight?
Yes Sergeant.
Should be easy for you then.
Corporal.
Make sure you keep this
man away from strong winds.
Yes, Sergeant.
- Private idiot.
- Yes Sergeant.
Raise your foot.
Higher.
Everyone outside now.
Move it.
I said move it.
I'm just getting my uniform Sarge.
Did I asked him to Corporal?
No memory of it Sarge.
I believe any man who take such
pride in his natural naked state.
Will surely enjoy the
brisk of the outdoors.
Now move your private, Private Parts.
Move it.
You son of an exhibitionist.
I'm gonna teach you how
to tie a bowline knot.
So you can get your sorry
asses down from a height.
So I make them kicked 'em.
Create a loop.
This is the rabbit hole.
The rabbit comes out of his hole.
Runs around the tree.
Goes back into the hole.
Alright.
Let's go.
Very good Texas.
Keep struggling Teach.
Have you ever rope a goat, Hollywood?
No Sarge.
- Have you ever looked into a goat's eye.
- No sarge.
Good. That would be unnatural.
You know if you don't breath you'll die.
Good Private Idiot.
Congratulations Greaseball, you just
fell fifty feet and broke your neck.
Brilliant.
Private Vito Rinnelli.
You strangle yourself numb nuts.
Are you a fan of Benilli?
No Sergeant.
You're American you'd be taller.
What do we got here Doss?
One for each titty
You're tying a bowline boy.
Not building a bra.
- What is so funny Corporal?
- Couldn't tell you Sergeant.
Come on.
Come on ladies.
Pick it up.
Move it. Move it.
I wanna see some fire here.
A little hustle.
Show me something.
Run like you need it.
Down. Down. Down.
Let's go trash town boys.
Move. Move. Move.
I wanna see you got it.
Let's go.
Get in. Get in. Get in.
Don't forget behind your ears.
Let's go. Move!
I bet you're enjoying
this naked degenerate.
Let's go.
Hustle. Hustle. Hustle.
Move.
Let's go. What are we waiting on.
Let's go.
Move your ass.
Get the wood. Get the wall.
Don't kiss quitters.
Drive. Drive.
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine.
What the hell is wrong with you?
No one says take a rest.
Move your asses to the finish line.
Move.
Hustle. Hustle.
Get your asses across damn line.
Aye, nice work Doss.
This is a personal gift
from the United States
government to each
and everyone of you.
Standard issue U.S. rifle.
Caliber 30.
M1
A clipboard.
Shoulder fired semi
automatic weapon designed
to bring death and
destruction to the enemy.
This is to be your lover.
Your mistress.
Your concubine.
Perhaps.
The only thing in life
you ever truly love.
Built with light stands.
Grab a girl.
Don't point your gun forward.
I do not want to be shot today.
No matter how much
you are tempted.
Place the weapon by your side.
Pay attention.
Problem private corn stock?
Is there not one in your size?
Or is it the color that is the issue?
No Sarge.
I was told I don't have
to carry a weapon.
Come again step forward Private.
I can't be hearing this right.
Well I'm sorry Sergeant.
I can't touch a gun.
What exactly is the problem?
No problem just a mistake.
- I told the army when I joined up.
- It's impossible.
You know why it's not possible, Private?
No, Sir.
Cause the United States
Army do not make mistakes.
There's a problem.
You must be that problem.
I was never supposed to be
sent to a rifle company.
He's a CO sir.
You're a conscientious objector.
- And you joined the army.
- Well no sir.
I'm a conscientious cooperator.
- You just screwing with me Doss.
- No. No sir. I volunteered.
I got no problem with wearing my uniform.
Saluting the flag and doing my duty.
It's just carrying a gun
and taking a human life.
You don't kill. That's all.
Yes sir. That's all.
You know quite a bit of
killing does occur in a war.
Yes, sir.
I mean that is the
essential nature of war.
Yes sir.
Alright.
You have any other requirements
for the United States army.
Is there anything else that
we can do to ensure that
you're comfortable with
your stay here with us?
He doesn't wanna work on Saturday, sir.
Well Saturday is. I'm a
Seventh Day Adventist so.
Saturday is my sabbath so I'm
not allowed to work then.
I don't think that poses a problem.
Do you sergeant?
We should simply ask the
enemy not to invade on a Sabbath
cause Private Doss
here is a prayer.
Alright. Now we got that clear.
Now let me tell you my requirements.
They're not as
complicated as yours.
They are very simple.
As long as you're in this
company under my command.
You're gonna obey my orders.
Period.
If you can't do it here. I can't
trust you to do it in the battle.
I'm putting you in for Section 8.
Psychiatric discharge.
Dismiss.
Gentlemen.
I want you to meet
Private Desmond Doss.
Apparently.
Private Doss does not
believe in violence.
He does not practice violence.
He will not even deign to touch a weapon.
You see Private Doss
is a conscientious objector.
So I plead with you.
Do not look to him to save
you on a battlefield.
Because he will undoubtedly be too busy
wrestling with his conscience to assist.
- Sarge, that's not true, sarge.
- Private as you were.
I realize some of you might have
strong feelings about this.
It is what we men fight for.
To defend our rights.
To protect our women and children.
Even if Private Doss's belief
might cause women and children to die.
So I will expect every
one in this company
to give Private Doss the full
measure of respect he is due.
For the short time he will be with us.
Am I clear?
Yes, sergeant.
What you got here Daisy?
- You know what that is?
- Just seems kind of small.
It's half-the-Bible
for half-the-man.
Pete's sake, Smitty give
him back his Bible.
I don't remember
speaking with you.
So how come you don't fight?
Do you think you better than us?
No.
Well, what if you're attacked.
Woah.
Did you like that?
Bible says to turn your other cheekbone.
You see I don't think this is a
question of religion, fellas.
I think this is cowardice.
Plain and simple.
You alright Doss?
You chickenshit that it?
Go on.
Take a poke.
Okay I'm gonna give a free shot.
Right there.
Hit me Doss.
Go on.
No?
- What is this?
- Give me that.
This is fine looking broad.
- Wooooh.
- Nice.
Now this would be the kind of broad.
That deserve a real man.
Give me that back.
Please.
Please give it back, Smitty.
Do you hear voices Desmond?
No, Sir.
I understand that God talks to you.
Is that right?
Sir, I'm not a crazy person.
Then how you feel most people regard you
Crazy person.
I'm different I know that. But
I'm not gonna pretend to
be something I'm not.
I am what I am.
Sounds lonely.
You lonely?
So you don't hear voices.
No, sir.
I pray to God and I
like to think He hears me but
it ain't a conversation.
Like how I won't gonna pretend we
have right now.
Pretending, private?
Yes, sir. I know what
you really wanna do is
is give me a section 8 draw
me out of the army. But
I'm not.
Up above.
I just simply believe
what I believe.
Well I'm trying to understand.
Alright? Was it God who told
you not to pick up a rifle?
God says not to kill.
That one of His most
important commandments.
Most people take that to
only don't commit murder.
War is completely different
set of circumstances.
Jesus said a new commandment
I give them to you.
That you love one another.
Just as I love you.
This is Satan himself we're fighting.
Sure as
good Christian you can see that.
I can see that sir and
that is why I joined up.
But I'm sorry I will not bear arms.
His religious view is
certainly unique but they
do not constitute ground
for Section 8 discharge.
How am I suppose to maintain
discipline with a man like that in my unit?
I don't know.
But he is a legitimate
conscientious objector.
He must be allowed to work
as combat medic provided
he qualifies in all other
areas in his training.
Perhaps we could help
make alleviate his idea.
Yeah you restrict him to barracks in KP.
He throws God at you.
You throw hell right at him.
I want him gone.
Doss your area is in disgrace.
It's a pig stock.
- Something funny Ryker?
- No sarge.
- You got some shit on your mind?
What you men fail to recognize
is a unit is no better
than its weakest member.
I hope you learned that lesson.
There will be no passes this weekend.
You all will be on KP.
Right now everybody on full
gear for 20-mile hike.
Let's go.
Get your heads right.
Don't start feeling sorry for yourself.
Makes me sick seeing you
feel sorry for yourself.
You dogs don't know
what tired is.
We gonna keep going till I drop.
Come on guys.
Hey knock it. Knock it off.
Trying to sleep here.
Get off me.
Get off.
Why the hell you still here?
- Ten-hut.
- As you were.
Where's Doss?
This isn't good for you buddy.
Sure ain't what I joined up for.
It's not about what you joined up for.
About the lives of
every men in here.
And yours son.
It's time you quit this.
Finish getting dress and
I'll walk you down.
It's okay Doss.
There's no shame in this.
Let's go.
I got an extra guard duty.
Today and I'm on KP this morning. So
I can't.
Alright Doss.
Private Doss.
Can you identify the men that beat you?
No sarge.
Are you saying that you
don't know who attack you?
I never said I was attacked sarge.
What the hell are you saying Doss?
You bruised half your body sleeping.
I sleep pretty hard.
Planning on getting wet this
week make sure you put on a hat.
I don't want anyone back piss in cream.
What you don't want to
offer your coffee sarge.
How about a shot right now Smitty?
Speaking from experience sarge.
You have to ask your mom
about that greaseball.
At ease.
Private Doss.
I'm afraid I can't authorize your pass.
This is a furlough for men who
had pass the basic training.
Respectfully sir I have.
I put in for this
furlough three weeks ago.
I'm getting married
this afternoon.
It says you're not
rifle-qualified.
Well I'm not required to carry a rifle, sir.
Colonel Colonel Stelzer he he...
Colonel Stelzer stipulation was
Doss must be allowed to
work as a combat medic.
Provided he qualifies in all
other areas of his training.
And you have not qualified
on the rifle range, private.
Pretty clear.
Show me you know how
to handle a rifle.
And I'll sign your furlough.
Corporal Cannon.
Hand private Doss your firearm.
I won't touch a rifle, sir.
I'm not asking you private.
That is a direct order
from a company commander.
For God's sake Doss.
You stop this nonsense and quit.
Refuse.
And I will have no recourse
but to court martial you.
And you will spend the duration
of the war in military prison.
I can't, sir.
How much longer would you
like to wait, Dorothy?
I think it's been long enough.
I'm so very sorry.
Sometimes men just get cold feet.
Some men might.
Not my Desmond.
You probably thinking I'm
a really son of a bitch.
Who cares only about
regulations and not his men.
May I.
I believe in this Book as much as any men.
Just like any men.
I wrestled with my conscience.
But what do you do when everything you
value in this world is under attacked.
I don't know, sir.
I ain't got answer to question that big.
But I also feel like my
values are under attacked.
I don't know why.
I don't give a rat-ass about your
principles because the Japs don't.
If one of them attacks you and some
wounded soldiers. What are you gonna do?
Hit him with your Bible?
I'm prepare to give my life for my men.
You don't win wars by giving up your life.
Look.
I'm only here because I don't wanna see
you rotting in a prison cell.
Plead guilty.
Put yourself at the mercy of the court.
Maybe they'll let you go home and pray.
Let the brave men out there
go and win this war.
If I can't convince
you maybe she can.
They wouldn't let me call you.
I know it wasn't your making.
What did they done to you?
It's okay I'm alright.
Just a couple of rounds
with a wall and lost.
They're saying you could
go to prison Desmond.
It'll never worth.
There must be some other way.
I don't know what that could be.
I done everything they'd asked
me except this one thing.
They've been treating me like a
criminal just cause I won't kill.
You tried.
Nobody can say you didn't.
But who you gonna save in prison?
Probably nobody.
Then why can't you just pick up the
stupid gun and wave it around.
You don't have to use it.
Just made it half-way.
I can't do that.
Yes, you can. It's just pride.
Pride and stubbornness.
Don't confuse your will with the Lord's.
I've been proudfull.
Maybe I'm proudful.
But I don't know how I'm
gonna live with myself
if I don't stay true to what I believe.
Watching us how you could live with me.
I wanna be a man and I
wanna be in your eyes.
I fell in love with you.
Because you weren't like anyone else.
And you didn't try to be.
Do not think for one moment
that you'll disappoint me.
I will love you.
No matter what.
I don't know what he's gonna do.
He loses no matter what.
They want him to plead guilty but
then it'll get him dishonorable discharge.
Otherwise he fights them he
will for sure go to prison.
Either way they'll call him a coward and
I don't see how he can live with that.
Thank you Dorothy.
If you get to talk to him.
Tell him that we love him and that we'll
pray for him and we'll pray for both of you.
I will.
Bye-bye.
Of course I'm out of my mind.
What do you think I am.
I'm out of my mind.
Will you leave this room.
Don't Tom. Put it down.
Get away from me woman.
May I help you sir?
I wish to speak to Brigadier
General Musgrove.
Not without an appointment you can't.
That would be quite impossible.
If you would kinda tell me Corporal Thomas
Doss would've appreciate a brief word.
He is in a very important meeting.
I fought with him in France at
Belleau Wood. He was my Captain.
Please maam. It's most vital.
Be over in a minute.
You'll be home safe and sound
like nothing ever happened.
This is a hearing in the
matter of Private Doss.
The charge is disobeying a series of
direct orders from his commanding officer.
How says the defendant?
Private Doss wishes to
enter a not guilty plea.
Is that so Private? I
thought this was agreed.
You want to enter some
sort of plea bargain.
- Yes, sir. But I changed my mind.
- Just like that?
You wish to proceed
to a court martial.
Yes, sir.
Your on your head then Private.
Proceed.
Your honor.
Private Doss.
Wave his morality like it's
some kind of badge of honor.
He flaunts his contempt.
By directly disobeying a series of direct
order from his commanding officer.
When the very best of our young men
are sacrificing their lives against evil.
- You okay?
- Yes.
- They still deliberating?
- Yes, sir.
Okay you go take this in there.
I can't. It's strictly
military personnel.
Well you get one of
them to take it in.
They ain't no help. They're
fixing to burying him.
There's only one question that any
military court need ask of the accused.
Do you deny disobeying Colonel
Sangston's direct orders?
Well. Do you private?
No, sir. I don't.
Why are you contesting it, then?
Why is it so important to
you, given your refusal to even
touch a weapon to
serve in a combat unit?
Because when the Japanese attacked
Pearl Harbor, I took it personal.
Everyone I knew was on fire
to join up, including me.
There were two men in my hometown
Declared 4-F unfit, they killed
themselves cause they couldn't serve.
Why, I had a job in a
defense plant.
I could've taken a deferment,
but that ain't right.
It isn't right that other
men should fight and die
that I would just be sitting at home safe.
I need this, sir.
I got the energy and the
passion to serve as a medic,
right in the middle with the other guys.
No less danger, just...
while everybody else is taking
life, I'm going to be saving it.
With the world so set on
tearing itself apart,
it doesn't seem like
such a bad thing to me
to wanna put a little bit
of it back together.
Sorry sir, nobody is allowed in.
No. You don't understand.
My son is the defendant.
- I understand sir. Nobody is allowed
- I have information.
Well, the sentiments
expressed are laudable.
The effects of the charge
is incontestable so
What the hell is going on out there?
Let him go.
That's the Great War uniform.
It is, sir.
Sir, I need to show you this.
With respect, sir.
You are no longer a
member of the military.
You unable to attend this meeting.
I'm sorry.
Is that truly the way it works?
You fight for your country
You lose so much ever dear to you.
And then you're done with?
Uniform's forgotten. You have no voice?
You were enlist?
I was sir Belleau Wood.
Twice decorated. I see it sir.
I take it you're the father.
I am, sir. Thomas Doss.
Then as former military man.
You know there are laws here.
Sir, I know the law. I am. I know my
son is protected by those laws.
They are framed in our constitution.
And I believe in them as he does.
That's why I went and
fought to protect them.
It's what I thought I was
doing because if it wasn't for
that then I have no idea what the
hell I was doing there, sir.
Thank you Corporal Doss.
Let me have the letter.
You must go.
The defendant's rights as
a conscientious objector
are protected by an Act of Congress.
And he cannot be compelled
to waive those rights.
That includes in this case his
disobeying orders to bear arm.
Signed Bridgadier General Musgrove. War
Services Commander, Washington DC.
Colonel.
I withdraw the charges.
Then this case is dismissed.
Private Doss you are free to
run into the hell fire of
battle without a single
weapon to protect yourself.
You may resume your duties.
Begin training as a combat medic.
- Where is he?
- Gone.
Straight after. I begged him to stay.
I told him he want the same.
When you get home you
tell him that I love him.
Okay.
You better come home to me.
♫ Uncle Sam is smiling.
Peaceful as a child. ♫
♫  But never get him rowdy. ♫
Cut it out, Tom.
So now you wanna play?
C'mon pipe down.
Shut up man.
Put a sock in it boy. You save the
choral for when we get there.
Your driver is here.
Give 'em room.
- Clear.
- Clear blue sky.
96th.
What's left of 'em.
These are the guys who replaced them.
Seems good to me.
It's cool.
All clear sarge.
Captain Glover.
Lieutenant Manville. 96th.
We've been assigned to you, sir.
Okay.
- Let's get these men some chow.
- Yes, sir.
- This is Sergeant Howell.
- Good to meet you sir.
Who's Doss?
Over there.
You Doss?
Irv Schecter
You and me and peach here.
About the only medics we
got left in this area. So
I guess we're going to
be working together.
You just come off the line?
What's it like?
I said what's it like?
Hacksaw?
We caught it about six times.
Six times they threw us off.
Last time wasn't anything
left for something to fix.
They're animals.
Stinking animals.
Nips don't care if they live or die.
They wanna die.
They keep coming at you.
They never gonna give up.
Never.
Hey buddy.
The Japs deliberately target the wounded.
Lose all your red cross markings.
Nips put a premium on shooting medics.
That white's a bull's-eye.
Here I got you a new helmet.
One-size-fits-all.
That's our objective.
Hacksaw Ridge.
We take it.
Maybe we get Okinawa.
We get Okinawa.
We take Japan.
Take a breather.
Our pals in the Navy are
gonna soften them up for us.
Nobody can survive that shit.
Oh, but they can.
Lieutenant.
This bunkers here. Here and here.
Is that accurate?
Yes, sir.
[Nauseous]
Yes, sir. Maybe they are gonna look
from the back but that's all.
It's all different.
Up there.
[All here accounted.]
Gents.
Move out!
It's blood.
No shit.
We're not in Kansas
anymore Dorothy.
Keep climbing.
Here. Come on give me your hand.
Make way.
Ralph, get this to Jessop.
Incoming!
Get down!
Where the hell are they?!!!
I can't see them!!!
Where the fuck?!!!
Medic!
Over here!
Put your hand right here.
Put your hand on that gut.
Come on. We're gonna
get you under cover.
Keep moving forward.
Can't see anything.
It's that one.
I dunno where to shoot.
Alright let's go.
Dino.
Oh shit!
Doss, Dino's down.
I'm coming.
Get out of the way!
You hurt?
I'm fine.
Come on! I got you.
Breath.
Just breath.
It's okay.
I got you.
Hey! Hey!
Give him a shot of morphine
and move on.
He's not gonna last a day.
Please. Please Doss.
No. No.
Don't leave me.
Please don't leave me.
I got kids.
Please! Please dont!
Please don't leave me!
I ain't going anywhere!
I'm going to get you home.
I got you Ralph.
Okay!
I'm gonna get you home.
Here's come the morphine.
Just gonna kick it real quick, Ralph.
We gonna get you shifted.
Stretcher!
Get up!
Keep moving!
Sergeant. I'm wounded.
There's nothing wrong with you.
Shit!
Hang on kid.
Move!
A soldier who doesn't is a dead one.
You forgotten priority.
Priority. You haven't of triage?
He'll be dead before we get 'em down.
Get him down!
Alright!
Huh!
- Okay.
Okay. Go!
It's alright buddy. We
gonna get you home.
Medic!
Help! Help!
I figured if we can't see them and
they can't see us neither.
Help!
I took it bad.
I got it Frank.
Where you hit?
I think they just did smart ass!
Give me your hand here.
Get down sir.
Over there!
The bunkers!
I do. Better stay down sir.
I got 'em!
Dead ahead!
Yeah. I see them too.
Get ready give 'em everything you got.
I'll sent them a weapon's
team to flank them.
Be there tight.
You gonna be right as new.
I got it Doss.
Got it.
You doing okay?
Okay.
Fire!
Go!
Son of a bitch!
Get 'em. Get on it!
- Yes sir.
- Now!
Smoke!
Corpsman.
Go!
Go! Go! Go for it!
Get in the hole.
Mother...
Go!
Be strong!
Cover!
Satchels!
Ghoul!
Here!
C'mon stick it.
Stick it Ghoul.
Cover! Cover!
Son of a...
Cover his ass!
Go!
Medic!
I'm here.
Put your hand on it.
Put your hand on it!
Go! Go! Go!
Ghoul.
Where you hit?
I don't know.
You not hit in the
head that's okay.
What's your name?
Andy.
Andy what?
Andy Walker.
Also known as?
- Ghoul.
Ghoul you're okay.
You're okay.
Good job men.
Good work.
Take it for the night.
We hold this spot.
We mop up the rest of
the ridge tomorrow.
Okay boys.
Find yourself a nice safe hole.
End or near the bunker.
We'll take watch every two hours.
We don't know what's out there.
Heads down, asses lower.
Shoot anything that
don't speak English.
That includes grease Sarge?
Particularly him.
I don't care if he needed
to take a piss or a dump.
It ain't safe to
go out there alone.
Where the hell you going Doss?
Still more wounded out there sarge.
I'll go with him.
Be smart keep your ears down.
Alright let's find a spot.
You know Henry dead in
the first 15 minutes.
Just straight off.
It's straight off.
Peterson.
Popeye.
Stanford and Murphy.
In peace sons bury their father.
In war fathers bury their sons.
Wanna stop spouting that crap out?
It don't help none.
Yeah.
Yeah, you got that right.
Not here.
Hey.
Give me that.
Hey!
We got an abdominal wound.
This lad is gonna need some plasma.
- You got it.
- He'll be with us.
We got you.
Should we find a hole and dig in.
Sounds good to me.
Put your helmet on.
You gonna eat them?
I don't eat meat.
Help yourself.
Of course you don't.
That's one heck of a dame.
You know you find that you
whack us with her don't you?
Yes, I do.
Don't tell her that.
She won't be much happy
with a man like me anyway.
Yeah until she got to know you.
I'm an asshole sometimes.
Sometimes.
You're alright.
These Japs are sneaky.
I take first watch.
Now you get a shut eye.
Hell of a dream.
I dreamed I got myself killed.
I can't do nothing.
Rifles will just do.
It won't bite.
Yeah, well.
Look around you.
After what we've been through.
Any sane man would be
screaming for a weapon.
I never claimed to be sane.
My daddy's a drunk.
He fought it for years but it kinda got
a hold of him hard and made him mean.
At least you know when mine could've
been with any one of the ten guys
And none of them
would worth a damn.
So your momma raise you?
I knew her.
But she gave me to an
orphanage when I was five.
Never saw her again.
I know how to act quick.
But now I judge people quicker
and I got you very wrong.
My dad used to beat me
and my brother just
cause the sun rose and
whip us cause it sets.
I could take that.
But when he would do it to our momma.
That's enough. No more.
Do you hear me?
Pull that damn trigger.
Don't Desmond. Stop!
But you didn't kill 'em.
In my heart I did.
So that's why I made my promise to God,
I ain't never gonna touch a gun again.
Well I ain't giving you
mine cause you're crazy.
Move! Move!
Get your assess over there!
- Why don't we let's go.
- Go! Go!
Go back! Fall back!
Go!
They're coming from underground!
Sir! Sir! This is riker six
request immediate support!
Target is North Thirty Five One Five
Don't you notice where you are?
Yes, I notice where the hell we are but
I don't expect to be here much longer.
I called an artillery strike!
Fall back!
Move! Move!
Get some!
Cover me!
Go! Go!
Argh!
Get out of here, kid!
Come here, son!
You know what to do!
Keep pressure on it!
No! Don't need plasma!
Give it to him!
Over there!
I'll be okay. Go!
Go!
- Reece!
- What?!!!
- Get on the back!
- You got it!
Okay see you soon.
C'mon. C'mon!
We gotta move right now!
C'mon! C'mon!
Move! Move!
I'm scared. I'm scared.
This gonna help the pain.
No! Don't! Dont'!
Don't you do that!
C'mon!
C'mon Smitty you stay with me!
Let's go we gotta move!
Hey! Help me get him down.
Help me get him down!
Come on let's roll.
Come on.
Can't help you buddy. He's gone.
No.
Come on.
We got to get out of here.
Down the rope!
After it.
Where does it He want me?
I don't understand.
I can't hear You.
Help me!
Alright!
How many?
32 only came down, sir.
Good Lord.
- Let sow them up.
- Yes, sir.
Harry.
It's Desmond.
We gonna fix you up.
You just gotta keep breathing. Okay
Colonel want to see you, sir.
I need your jeep.
You two stay here and keep watch.
Keep your eyes peel for Japs.
No. But the...
Stay here and keep watch!
Yes, sir.
Help! Help me.
Watch out!
I got you.
Put your hand on it.
Keep pressure on it.
I'm coming back.
- Okay.
- Don't leave.
Easy fellas.
Easy.
Here we go.
Okay guys let's go.
Coming through.
One-Two-Three.
Move.
It's okay.
Just sit tight, okay.
You okay buddy.
Son of a gun. This is gonna work
One for each leg.
We gonna get you dress up in a jiffy.
and get you down.
I got you.
I got you now.
You can trust me.
Japs!
Hold on. One of ours.
Hold on.
Let's go. Let's go.
I got you.
Come on.
You okay.
Hey!
Another one.
Colonel. Call off the artillery attack
on Hacksaw. Couldn't pull it in.
There's still over a 100
men left out there.
Tell them to call off the
artillery on Hacksaw.
[Radio]
Able-Baker-One over.
Sit down Jack.
I get you a drink.
Just lost our cover.
They're starting.
We gotta move.
About time.
They just keep coming.
- Okay.
- Pick it up.
I got this.
Doss.
Help.
Help me.
You gonna have to trust me.
Take a breath.
Let's go buddy.
Let's go.
Jack. You don't know if your men
out there are dead or alive.
We can't go back up there
without reinforcement.
You'll end up killing the rest.
So give me the reinforcement.
I don't have any fresh men.
I don't have any troops.
3 battalions got wipe out today.
And it'll take more than a
day to get men here.
I need them faster than that.
It's okay. It's okay.
It's alright. It's alright.
It's okay.
Morphine it's good.
Shhh.
Medic. Medic.
Medic. It's Doss.
It's Doss. Be quiet.
Be quiet.
We got you. Where you hit?
I can't see.
Be quiet. Just be quiet.
Hold still now.
I got you.
Hold tight.
There you go.
Try that. Try that.
I thought I was blind.
Shhh.
Keep it down.
Can you walk?
I don't know.
- Cause we gotta get out of here.
- Okay.
Okay we got you.
We got you.
Hey, there.
It's me Desmond.
Fix you up.
You ready to get out here.
I'm sure am.
Please Lord.
Help me get one more.
Please help me get one more.
One more.
Help me get one more.
Coming through.
Where the hell these
guys coming from?
Hacksaw.
I thought they pulled out.
Not all of them.
Some nuts out there drive
the wounded from the top.
Even lowered a couple of Japs.
They didn't make it.
Get back with you directly.
Easy. Easy.
All set. Move out.
Let's go.
Get in here.
There's Nips everywhere.
Son of a bitch.
Private corn stock.
You're nothing if not
full of surprises.
You want some morphine.
- Hell yes.
That or both.
Okay.
There.
There you go.
Alright.
Easy. Let me see.
How's this?
Okay. Not bad.
Let me see.
I'll make much much than this.
But girls still won't kiss you.
Sarge.
You okay here for a while?
Yeah I'm fine.
Get outta here.
I'm coming back.
You ready?
Let's go.
You and me. C'mon.
Captain.
Something you gotta see.
Our guys have been coming
down in droves all night.
And Hollywood's here.
I never thought I'd
see that guy again.
Come on follow me.
He's right here.
What the hell is this?
How you doing sir?
Hey, Cap.
Captain.
It's good to see you kid.
God bless, sir.
How you get down, son?
It's Doss.
Howell's still out there.
Howell and Doss did this?
No, sir. It's just Doss.
- Just Doss?
- Just Doss.
Yeah Doss the Coward.
You like gum on a shoe ain't ya.
Give me this.
It's a bit late for target
practice now don't you think.
Jump on it.
You kidding?
No, I'm gonna drag you.
Let's do it.
- Ready?
- Yeah
Let's go!
We got company.
Come on.
We're gonna jump.
You gotta be kidding
me, corn stock?
You got a bowline, not building a bra.
Come on!
- Ready?
- Ah huh.
Get off!
- Put me down!
- Yes, Sergeant.
Sergeant Howell.
Doss is still up there.
What the hell?
He's got Japs on his tail.
We got him.
It's good. It's good.
Woah. It's okay. It's okay. Doss.
You're safe.
Okay.
Desmond.
Easy.
Here come on.
Take a seat.
Are you wounded?
No.
Let's get this soldier to a
hospital tent right now.
Come on easy now.
Easy. Easy.
Where's Irv?
Irv.
You mean Schecter the Medic?
He didn't make it.
He died of shocked.
No plasma.
Sorry.
All I saw was a skinny kid.
I didn't know who you were.
You done more than any other men could've
done in a service to his country.
I have never been more wrong
about someone in my life.
I hope one day you
could forgive me.
We have to go back up tomorrow.
I realize that tomorrow
is your Sabbath.
Most of these men don't
believe the same way you do.
They believe so much.
How much you believe.
What you did on that Ridge
is nothing short of miracle.
They wanna piece of it.
They're not gonna go
up there without you.
What the hell is your delay, Captain?
You supposed to begin that
assault 10 minutes ago.
We're waiting, sir.
Waiting for what?
Private Doss to finish praying for us, sir.
- Private Doss is praying for you.
- Who the hell is Private Doss?
Let's go to work.
Down!
Get down! Get down on the ground!
On the ground now!
Lay down! Lay down!
I got the morphine.
Let's go! Let's go.
Let's get this man outta here.
Go! Go!
My Bible.
Stop! Stop! Stop!
My Bible. My Bible.
Okay.
You going home Desmond.
We've taken the Hacksaw.
Hold up! Hold up!
Desmond.
I was praying the whole time.
I just start praying to the Lord
please let me get one more.
When I got this I said "Alright
Lord please help me get one more".
I would say anyone is wrong to try
to compromise somebody's conviction.
I don't care it's the army or what it is.
When you're on a conviction
That is not a joke.
That's what you are.
Even though I said those things to him
in regard to carrying a rifle.
Then he would never be on my damn
side at all unless he had a rifle.
But then in the long run.
Finding out that he was one
of the bravest person alive.
And then to have him ended up saving my
life was the irony of the whole thing.
Blood it ran down through this
fellow's face and eyes.
It was when that he go
in and called for medic.
I took the water from my
canteen and got some bandages.
And I wash his face.
And when I wipe.
Washed up his eyes.
Eyes came out
Man, he just lit up.
He says I thought I was blind.
And if I hadn't got anything
more to that smile he gave me.
I wouldn't have been well repaid.
Psagmeno.com
MOViE iNFO WiTH .srt FiLES!